I'm great. If y'all just sit down wherever you are, you go back to your seats. Here's what I know
I'm coming in ruined. I'm coming in heavy
for the last
24 hours, I will say that I have I haven't been able to really talk to eat. I feel I feel
Trembly at what I believe God wants to do tonight in this room
And I I just take it seriously that
It feels like we're living in urgent times
and
this urgency that has
consumed me is
only growing and
When you have urgency in your bones, like I have urgency in my bones right now
You just I don't have it in me to come up with a little funny talk
Starter opener thing and so we're just diving right in. Are y'all are y'all good with it? Yeah, I
Think we've gotten lukewarm
And
The time is calling us
To be red-hot and if that is the case the scripture says
That I will spit you out of my mouth
The scripture I read earlier in Revelation would go on and say I will remove my lampstand from you church
my witness
My spirit my glory. I will remove the light from within you
if
You remain in love with anything more than me
I
Fear
That I may become like the preachers of old
that talk about hell and
brimstone why
because 5.5 billion people currently are perishing that we know of and
The weight of
Glory is something I'm akin to I have been in the rooms. I have felt the glory of God present
I was in Asbury. I was in SCU when the Spirit of God and an outpouring happened there
I've been in probably 30 to 40 rooms that I would term
Revival different than other rooms that I have seen God move in a mighty way. I
Have seen the glory of God
I have felt the weight of glory and what I am convicted of as of late is
That I have not felt the weight of my own sin. I
Have preached a cheap grace because I have believed I am better than I am
And so here we stand
Here we stand aware of where this will go which is going to be to end with the grace the great grace of God
But before we can experience the glory we have to understand what it cost
And that I stand before you truly as
The worst of sinners and what I mean by that is I am self-obsessed I
Still care what people think of me. I
Do not want a life where people don't respect me
I care that you know my name and you'd probably don't I haven't even introduced myself
And
In 1994 the Hubble telescope
The most powerful telescope at that point would zoom into the darkest place in space
I
Talked to an astronaut yesterday and he gave me this very penny and he said Jenny I want you to understand that
that that telescope went
To what would be equivalent to a penny in the world
To the eyeball of Abraham Lincoln on the penny and to the place where it looked like there was nothing
and
So the telescope would take all of the universe
zoom into a penny and
There would be even a smaller portion than that that it would see and
When it zooms in to the littlest speck of universe
There were lights so many they couldn't count them
There
Were lights so many they couldn't count them and they weren't stars
Every light that they saw in a speck of the universe was a galaxy
And
I want to be someone and I want to matter and I want to be something
Who am I?
Before God like that
We soberly sit
tonight
without a doubt in
the presence of the God who formed galaxies in
Nuber and we find ourself in one of the galaxies in
One of the solar systems in one of the planets in a little room in
Dallas, Texas
Taking for granted that a God who formed galaxies would meet with us
And so I tremble
And
I believe that the work we do here if the presence of God would come
to the smallest little dot in his galaxy to commune with us I
Suggest we take it seriously. I
Don't know you
You've come from all over some of you are porch people. I know you it's my home church
This is where I get to do life Kylan is a friend
But what I do know is I just watched you worship and my sense is you've come to meet with God
And
I want you I know what I'm up against because I assume that many of you are here
From this church or from another church, and you know the things of God this book for you is very familiar
This book for you is very familiar. Yes talk back to me team
If it isn't familiar
You're gonna love it and
Your friend might have tricked you
Made you come with them
But you're gonna love this book and you're gonna love the God we preach about
But for tonight what I want you to do is I want you to imagine you've never heard any of it
All you've done is observed creation
All you've you've done is you've observed humans that you know, and you've never heard of this God that built it all
Okay
You with me?
And I want you to imagine that what we're about to talk about
What I'm about to read with you what I'm about to work through with you is the only thing you knew of this God
Can you imagine with me we're gonna be in Luke 15
Luke 15 verse 11
And
Jesus continued in his sharing and
He shares this story
He says there was a man who had two sons and the younger one said to the father father
Give me my share of the estate
So he divided his property between them and not long after that the younger son got together all he had and he set off for a
far country a distant country and then
Squandered his wealth in wild living so I want you to picture
two boys
one of them spits in his father's face and
Says I want I want it to be as if you are dead and I want you to give me what is already
Will be mine will already be mine and I'm gonna take it with me and I'm out peace
and so he gets his inheritance and
He heads to a far country
Now
I want you to think about this as
someone
Who also at some point in your life
likely today has also
traveled to a far country
And what do you do? Okay, so so we're going to the far country. We're going to the land away from our father
We are going to the land. What are we doing? Why are we going? What why would we be going?
Why would we be leaving the estate of a rich father that wants to take care of us that loves us?
Why would we go?
Freedom freedom good. What else pleasure? What else?
Independence control great answers keep going what why do we leave it?
We think there's something better out there
What else?
curiosity
convenience rebellion
pride ego escape
New
We are
We are obsessed with
Running away from God
We don't even care
What is that the country that we are on our way to?
We just want our freedom
We don't want the burden we want to do what we want to do we want to have what we want to have
and
so the boy
Ran away to a far country. Now. The funny thing is about this distant country this far-off country is
We don't exactly know
its name
We don't know what he thought he would find
We don't know what he thought would be good about it
But he thought it was gonna be better than what he had and so he goes and he runs
And he runs after many many things so many things that whatever inheritance
that he had he squandered it and
the scripture says
That after he had spent everything there was a famine in the country and
He began to be in need and so he went and hired himself out to a citizen of that country
Who sent him to his fields to feed pigs?
He no longer
He longed so badly to fill his stomach
That basically he ate out of the pigsty
He ate what the pigs were eating because no one would give him anything
So father where we are like this son
We ask you that you convict us
Where we have have turned
Toward toward another place that offers other things that we think are better than you God would you convict our hearts?
Okay, so
Here's what I've found. I've been on college campuses. I have been in prisons. I have been in churches
I have been all over the world literally in different countries and I have seen
everything and I
somehow have found one of the roles in my life to be somewhat John the Baptist and I am
Doing repentance in all these places. So what I have is a very good pulse on
What we as a generation are struggling with I have heard it all you cannot believe the things I have heard
From every age in every setting. I have heard it all and
Here's what is interesting
At the end of all of the best things the world has to offer
Everyone is desperately empty
They are longing they are sick they are
starving
For something bigger and better than the far-off country. They have run to
and they want
To believe that they're loved and they want to believe that God is real
There have been times in history
That it feels like the morality of a place has kept it
From turning to Jesus
That is not today
There is a desperation in almost every room that I go to
Because they have gotten to the end of everything they thought they wanted and it isn't enough
Here's the thing
Revival is spreading. It is not a doubt. I just read an article and
You know what? I thought to myself you called the wrong people I can give you ten names
We are watching it happen in rooms like you cannot believe
Because they're saying like yeah, the numbers aren't really shifting first of all
The numbers are shifting and the Spirit of God is moving and people are going from darkness to light and I'm watching it all the time
Unlike it was ten years ago and
I deeply believe it is only the beginning
I deeply believe that we are heading not into just a season of revival for our country
But I believe that we are in the beginning the precipice of a great awakening
And I believe and this is wild stuff and I you can quit me
But I'll be just like the Apostles in doing so that I believe it could be the final great awakening
Preparing the way for Jesus to come back
It just wouldn't be crazy if
He came back in our lifetime. So what if he is what if it is imminent? What if what if it is near?
What are we wasting our lives with? What are we wasting our time with?
What are we giving our lives to?
And so I've seen it on college campus. I've seen everything and I'm gonna tell you right now
There is a cost to pay for revival
Like if if we want it, and I don't know what you want. Like what do you want? I don't know why you came
You came to me. I came to you. I came to you. I came to you
You may have come
For something other than God, but if you came for God like did you come for God?
Did you come are you praying? Do you believe like would you love to see revival?
Would you love to experience God in such a way that it absolutely changes you forever?
There is a cost to that I've seen it paid
I've seen it paid all over the earth
And I'll tell you what it is
Its repentance
I've seen it in
Every room that there has been revival. I have seen a wailing over sin. I
Have seen a genuine guttural
Depression sadness angst over sin
This year I was at Southeastern University and
My sweet friend well, is it a secret that they're coming? Okay. Well, I just told him
I see you worships coming tomorrow. So those are my those are my brothers and sisters because we saw God come down
Okay together. I'm
preaching and and
I lead a moment of repentance and and it's we're in a Christian college and and people are yelling out their sin and
They would go on to worship God for the next ten days and nights
They wouldn't stop they wouldn't leave they were they were wrecked they were ruined it was over
But I'll tell you the thing that happened like when the room broke
Everyone would tell you you can ask him when they come when did the room break?
Everyone I've asked would say the room broke open the outpouring of the Spirit of God fell on that place
When a woman in the very back
Who I would hear later
Was on her knees on her face weeping
and
She didn't confess right away
It would be minutes after we had started confessing
But my friend who was charging his phone in the back said Jenny I saw her go from her face
To stand up and
yell in this Christian College as
Loudly as she could from the back the entire room heard it
And then she crumbled to the ground weeping
What does it cost
Your reputation
What does it cost?
The thing that you have loved more than God, what does it cost the secret you have been keeping?
What does it cost to see God fall if my people will humble themselves and pray?
if
they will
Name their sins and turn from their wicked ways. I
Will pour out my spirit scripture says and I will heal their land
You
We're a dot in a galaxy
Among infinite galaxies
And the spirit of the Living God is saying that created all of the world and everything in it and every galaxy is saying
I
will
Come to you. I
Will heal you I will be with you if you humble yourself and you turn from your wicked ways
And so the far-off country
That we think is better
What do we do?
How do we come back to God what does it look like to humble ourselves and turn from our wicked ways
It's called repentance in the Bible
When he came to his senses verse 17 says
He's eating the crud of the world and he comes to his senses
That
Is what I am praying for this room that is what I cannot do for this room
That we as a people and individuals would come to our senses and see
that we have been going the wrong way and
Some of you you're like girl, I'm already saved I have walked with God for a long time like I know
and
some of you
Have been walking with God for a long time and you are literally walking in the wrong direction
All the while
With your arms raised singing to him
All the while serving him in ministry
all the while
Saying your sin, but never turning from it
Go into that country acting like you're walking toward God
Even believing yourself that you're walking toward God and
You wonder why you're anxious and isolated and distant
He came to his senses
He said what the heck am I doing I
Have a good father and
He treats his animals better than I am living right now
so maybe in
My wretchedness for how horrible I have wished he was dead. I have hated him and I have lived my own way
Whatever I wanted
maybe he would let me come back as a slave and
In that moment he does more than say I should go back to my father he turns and
He heads back to his father
He leaves the country he has given his life and wealth and time and thought and money
And body and everything - he leaves it and he says I'm going back home
To be a slave ah to be a slave in my father's house would be better
Are y'all with me?
It's the only thing you've ever heard about this God. Okay, you're about to you're about to just die you ready
Oh
It's so good
And
while
He was a long way off
His father saw him
His father saw and he was filled with compassion for him and he leaves his house and he runs
to his son and he threw his arms around him and he kissed him and
This son said to him father. I have sinned I have sinned and I've sinned against heaven and I've sinned against you
And I'm not even worthy to be called your son anymore
Who am I? I?
Have sinned
Like he didn't know
and
the son said to him father I
Have sinned against all of this and I'm no longer worthy to be your son
But the father said to his servants quick bring the best robe and put it on him put a ring on his
Finger and sandals on his feet bring the fattened calf and kill it
Let's have a feast and celebrate for the son of mine who was dead is alive again
He was lost and he is found so we will celebrate
This is our God
Here's the thing we think
We think it's better
We think it's better in the far-off country
And so we're scared to leave it
And yet there is a God
That it is clear in this scripture he's looking for you like he's waiting for you
His eyes are peeled for you like he's sitting there and his son from a far-off distance
Appears like a speck and he takes off he waits for us to come back
We have a father who's
Who is ready to give us everything our souls are craving and we're staying in the pigsty
So what shifts
How does it shift
We
Gotta want to go home
Like do you
Have you gotten to the end of it yet like how bad has it gotten for you
How much
Pain have you felt
My counselor he says this he says people don't usually change until it hurts bad enough
Does it hurt bad enough
Here's what I believe is happening I
Believe that God's Spirit is moving in a unique way right now
So
That the people that will bring in and usher the revival are ready and
Some of you are like I'm so far from that
That's not exactly where I am today like I just came to find a girl like I I'm not I'm just not there
Why
Have the things of God
Grown
Small to you
Because the book isn't a myth it's not pretend like this is happening. This is real like we are
We are living in history
God is coming and there is enormous work to do that will shape eternity
Are you in
But if you're in you got to weigh the cost
And it almost doesn't feel fair in this space
I know a lot of you probably are sitting with people that you love and know where's the section that like came alone
I thought are y'all sitting together
Y'all are so cool like I can't believe you did that so okay apart from this section most of you are sitting with someone you know
lucky you
Because here's what I want to do
What I want to do is I want to call this room to repentance
What God wants to happen is he wants this room to be convicted and not just convicted to name something
but be convicted to turn and leave it and
For us to turn and leave it we will need community
We will need a church. We will need to know this book. We will need to fight and
To believe that God can shift us from the inside
We've got to believe that tomorrow
Tuesday when we wake up
That that addiction is not stronger than the Holy Spirit that lives inside of us and that that love of sin is not
Stronger than the love of the Father that is waiting for us running towards us
Wrapping us up giving us everything we need we have to believe some things and then we have to do some things
It's both
Okay
So we're gonna believe some things that we're gonna do some things tonight
And I want to just start we're just gonna start like this
I want you to turn to the people that you prayed with and I want it to be the same gender and I want you
To go. Okay. I know what I have gone to the other country to get I
Have gone to the other country because I want a spouse
More than I want God
What if he doesn't have that for you?
It's a good desire
But are you willing to say God even if you don't have that for me? I'm not gonna live here. I'm coming back to you. I
Want to speak specifically to some things like porn alcohol drugs
Sexual addiction I want to speak to those things and here's why because let me be so clear
God is not sitting there going. I cannot believe the humans are looking at porn
He is just y'all he is not surprised he made sex he created it
But what he cannot believe is
that 65% of
men are
Addicted to porn outside of the church and the believers only 64%
There's only 1% separating the believers that are men and I know women it's one in three
So it's not like this isn't what he cannot believe
Is that the church doesn't know that he's better than porn?
We get God
We get God and we settle for things that feel good in a moment
That I see there are no toddlers here
We are not toddlers
We are more than conquerors
Not filled with a spirit of fear but of power of love and self-discipline church
and if life is only about this country
We could stay here and enjoy all these things
Without the thought of a father, but you cannot live in the far-off country and at home
You're in one or the other
You're with God or you're in sin like there's not really
Place and I'm not saying that at home
We don't struggle with temptation. We don't struggle with needed to confess regularly, but I'm saying are we home?
Are we with God because if we're with God we want to be about the work of turning every single day
This isn't a big step
It's an impossible step apart from God
Because everything in us wants to stay where it is comfortable, even though it will kill us
Rather than go home
But here's the thing when we go home
Doesn't feel like shame it feels like a party
It's
It's like the best day of this guy's life
And so I don't know if this is hard for you
I imagine it is and the reason I imagine it is is because I have to turn every day and it feels
hard
Until I do it and then probably like this pretend kid in the story
I'm like, why didn't I come home sooner?
So we're gonna do this right now. I want you to turn to
Someone of the same gender and I just want you to say like here it is
Like this is the thing and I want you to say the hard thing
I don't want you to say the easy thing. I want you to say the heavy thing
I want you to say the thing that you don't want to say whether it's
addiction of some kind
Or self-obsession. I want you to say what you need to say
To
Your neighbor are you in
Amen go I give you one minute do it fast
[BLANK_AUDIO]